Robert Porter Patterson Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Robert Porter Patterson Papers 1909-1956 1930-1952
MSS35626
Patterson, Robert Porter, 1891-1952
45,600 items
216 containers plus 1 classified
39.8 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Lawyer, judge, and U. S. secretary of war. Correspondence, memoranda, reports, and speeches reflecting Patterson's career as a jurist and service as assistant secretary, under secretary, and secretary of the War Department.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Arnold, Henry Harley, 1886-1950--Correspondence.; Arnold, Thurman Wesley, 1891-1969--Correspondence.; Baruch, Bernard M. (Bernard Mannes), 1870-1965--Correspondence.; Biddle, Francis, 1886-1968--Correspondence.; Bowles, Chester, 1901-1986--Correspondence.; Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1862-1947--Correspondence.; Byrnes, James F. (James Francis), 1882-1972--Correspondence.; Cardozo, Benjamin N. (Benjamin Nathan), 1870-1938--Correspondence.; Clark, Bennett Champ, 1890-1954--Correspondence.; Clark, Mark W. (Mark Wayne), 1896-1984--Correspondence.; Clay, Lucius D. (Lucius DuBignon), 1897-1978--Correspondence.; Conant, James Bryant, 1893-1978--Correspondence.; Cummings, Homer S. (Homer Stillé), 1870-1956--Correspondence.; Davis, Elmer, 1890-1958--Correspondence.; De Seversky, Alexander P. (Alexander Procofieff), 1894-1974--Correspondence.; Dewey, Thomas E. (Thomas Edmund), 1902-1971--Correspondence.; Doolittle, James Harold, 1896-1993--Correspondence.; Douglas, Paul H. (Paul Howard), 1892-1976--Correspondence.; Drum, Hugh Aloysius, 1879-1951--Correspondence.; Dubinsky, David, 1892-1982--Correspondence.; Dulles, Allen, 1893-1969--Correspondence.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969--Correspondence.; Farley, James A. (James Aloysius), 1888-1976--Correspondence.; Forrestal, James, 1892-1949--Correspondence.; Frankfurter, Felix, 1882-1965--Correspondence.; Graham, Philip L., 1915-1963--Correspondence.; Griswold, Erwin N. (Erwin Nathaniel), 1904-1994--Correspondence.; Gruening, Ernest, 1887-1974--Correspondence.; Hand, Augustus Noble, 1869-1954--Correspondence.; Hand, Learned, 1872-1961--Correspondence.; Hiss, Alger--Correspondence.; Hoffman, Anna Rosenberg, 1902-1983--Correspondence.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964--Correspondence.; Hughes, Charles Evans, 1862-1948--Correspondence.; Jessup, Philip C. (Philip Caryl), 1897-1986--Correspondence.; Johnson, Louis Arthur, 1891-1966--Correspondence.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973--Correspondence.; Jones, Jesse H. (Jesse Holman), 1874-1956--Correspondence.; Kefauver, Estes, 1903-1963--Correspondence.; King, Ernest Joseph, 1878-1956--Correspondence.; Klein, Julius, 1901-1984--Correspondence.; Knopf, Alfred A., 1892-1984--Correspondence.; Knudsen, William S., 1879-1948--Correspondence.; Landis, James M. (James McCauley), 1899-1964--Correspondence.; Lehman, Herbert H. (Herbert Henry), 1878-1963--Correspondence.; Lilienthal, David Eli, 1899-1981--Correspondence.; Lovett, Robert A. (Robert Abercrombie), 1895-1986--Correspondence.; MacArthur, Douglas, 1880-1964--Correspondence.; Marshall, George C. (George Catlett), 1880-1959--Correspondence.; McAdoo, W. G. (William Gibbs), 1863-1941--Correspondence.; McCarran, Pat, 1876-1954--Correspondence.; McGrath, J. Howard (James Howard), 1903-1966--Correspondence.; Minton, Sherman, 1890-1965--Correspondence.; Moses, Robert, 1888-1981--Correspondence.; Nelson, Donald Marr, 1888-1959--Correspondence.; Nizer, Louis, 1902-1994--Correspondence.; O'Dwyer, William, 1890-1964--Correspondence.; Patterson, Robert Porter, 1891-1952.; Patton, George S. (George Smith), 1885-1945--Correspondence.; Perlman, Philip B. (Philip Benjamin), 1890-1960--Correspondence.; Petersen, Howard C. (Howard Charles), 1910- --Correspondence.; Pound, Roscoe, 1870-1964--Correspondence.; Roberts, Owen J. (Owen Josephus), 1875-1955--Correspondence.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945--Correspondence.; Rosenman, Samuel I. (Samuel Irving), 1896-1973--Correspondence.; Royall, Kenneth C. (Kenneth Claiborne), 1894-1971--Correspondence.; Saltonstall, Leverett, 1892-1979--Correspondence.; Schlesinger, Arthur M., Jr. (Arthur Meier), 1917-2007--Correspondence.; Sherwood, Robert E. (Robert Emmet), 1896-1955--Correspondence.; Skouras, Spyros Panagiotes, 1893-1971--Correspondence.; Smith, H. Alexander (Howard Alexander), 1880-1966--Correspondence.; Somervell, Brehon Burke, 1892-1955--Correspondence.; Spellman, Francis, 1889-1967--Correspondence.; Spellman, Francis, 1889-1967.; Spivak, Lawrence E. (Lawrence Edmund), 1900-1994--Correspondence.; Stimson, Henry L. (Henry Lewis), 1867-1950--Correspondence.; Swope, Herbert Bayard, 1882-1958--Correspondence.; Symington, Stuart, 1901-1988--Correspondence.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972--Correspondence.; Tydings, Millard E. (Millard Evelyn), 1890-1961--Correspondence.; Vanderbilt, Arthur T., 1888-1957--Correspondence.; Voorhees, Tracy S. (Tracy Stebbins), 1890-1974--Correspondence.; Wagner, Robert F. (Robert Ferdinand), 1877-1953--Correspondence.; White, Walter, 1893-1955--Correspondence.; Wilson, Charles Edward, 1886-1972--Correspondence.
Organizations
American Association for the United Nations.; American Bar Association. Commission on Organized Crime.; American Committee on United Europe.; Atlantic Union Committee.; Catholic Church--Foreign relations.; Harvard Law School--Students.; Harvard Law School. Association (1886- ); Long Island Rail Road Commission.; Marshall Plan.; North Atlantic Treaty Organization.; Patterson, Belknap, Webb & Tyler (Firm); Permanent Court of Arbitration.; United Nations.; United States. Air Force--Reorganization.; United States. Army--Reorganization.; United States. Commission on Organization of the Executive Branch of the Government (1947-1949); United States. Committee for a United Nations Genocide Convention.; United States. Court of Appeals (2nd Circuit); United States. Department of Defense.; United States. District Court (New York: Southern District); United States. War Department.; United States. War Department. Office of the Assistant Secretary of War.; United States. War Department. Office of the Under Secretary of War.
Subjects
Courts--New York (State); Courts--United States.; District courts--New York (State); Draft.; Economic assistance, American--Europe.; International organization.; Morale.; Practice of law--New York (State); Security, International.; Strategy.; World politics--1945-1989.; World War, 1939-1945--Claims.; World War, 1939-1945--Europe.; World War, 1939-1945--United States.; World War, 1939-1945--Vatican City.; World War, 1939-1945.
Places
Europe--Economic conditions--1945-; Europe--Foreign relations--United States.; New York (N.Y.)--Politics and government--1898-1951.; New York (State)--Politics and government--1865-1950.; United States--Armed Forces--Appropriations and expenditures.; United States--Armed Forces--Demobilization.; United States--Armed Forces--Procurement.; United States--Armed Forces--Recruiting, enlistment, etc.; United States--Economic conditions--20th century.; United States--Foreign relations--Europe.
Occupations
Cabinet officers.; Judges.; Lawyers.
Acquisition Information
The papers of Robert Porter Patterson were given to the Library of Congress in two installments by Margaret Patterson. The first installment was deposited in the Library in 1953 and converted to a gift in 1959. The second installment was given in 1964. Additional material was donated in 2017 by Virginia P. Montgomery.
Additional Guides
Acquisition notes concerning the papers of Robert Porter Patterson appeared in the Library's Information Bulletin 13, no. 19 May 10, 1954) 1; and in the Quarterly Journal of Current Acquisitions 11, no. 3 (May 1954): 168 and 22, no. 4 (October 1965): 323.
Transfers
Items have been transferred from the Manuscript Division to other custodial divisions of the Library. Some photographs, photograph albums, and a presentation album have been transferred to the Prints and Photographs Division. A record album has been transferred to the Motion Picture, Broadcasting, and Recorded Sound Division. All transfers are identified in these divisions as part of the Robert Porter Patterson Papers.
Security Classified Documents
Government regulations control the use of security classified material in this collection. Manuscript Division staff can furnish information concerning access to and use of classified materials.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1891 Feb. 12 Born, Glens Falls, N.Y.
1912 A.B., Union College, Schenectady, N.Y.
1915 LL.B., Harvard Law School, Cambridge, Mass.
1915 Admitted to New York bar
1916 Served on Mexican border as a private in 7th Regiment, New York National Guard
1917 1919 Served in American Expeditionary Forces as a second lieutenant, later captain, then major in the 306th Infantry, 77th Division
1919 1922 Practiced law, firm of Root, Buckner and Howland
1920 Married Margaret T. Winchester (died 1988)
1922 1929 Practiced law, firm of Webb, Patterson and Hadley
1929 1930 Practiced law, firm of Murray, Aldrich and Webb
1930 1939 Judge, U.S. District Court, Southern District of New York
1937 1949 President, Harvard Law School Association
1939 1940 Judge, U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit
1940 Assistant secretary of war
1940 1945 Under secretary of war
1945 1947 Secretary of war
1947 1948 President, Association of the Bar of New York
1947 1952 Practiced law, firm of Patterson, Belknap, Webb, and Tyler
1950 1951 Chairman, Long Island Rail Road Commission
1951 Chairman, American Bar Association Commission on Organized Crime
1952 Jan. 22 Died, Elizabeth, N.J.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Robert Porter Patterson (1891-1952) span the years 1909-1956, with the bulk of the material concentrated between 1930 and 1952. The papers are organized into eight series: Correspondence, Legal File, Speech File, Miscellany, Scrapbooks, Under Secretary of War Files, 2023 Addition and Classified. The Correspondence series is further arranged into seven subseries differentiated mostly by chronological spans as compiled and maintained by Patterson before being received by the Library. Additional correspondence can be found in the 2023 Addition series.
The Legal File consists of briefs and memoranda on cases in which Patterson presided as a judge, correspondence concerning the cases, and notes taken or collected by him. Patterson served on the United States District Court for the Southern District of New York, 1930-1939, and on the United States Court of Appeals, Second Circuit, 1939-1940. The case material from his judgeships is filed alphabetically according to the type of case and therein alphabetically by name. The collection also contains a file of legal note by Patterson on a variety of subjects. These notes, along with Patterson's law school notebooks, illustrate the intensity of preparation and the care that went into his study of the law. In the Legal File as well is an index to Patterson's legal cases from 1930 to 1939 and memoranda concerning his legal cases from 1939 to 1940.
The Speech File, Scrapbooks, Miscellany, and Under Secretary of War Files are primarily concerned with Patterson's career as a government official. Also present are materials relating to his estate and to Margaret Patterson's donation of the collection to the Library.
The 2023 Addition series consists of outgoing correspondence documenting Patterson's professional activities in the latter years of his career, and speeches and statements given during and after his tenure as secretary of war.
Patterson's career covered a wide variety of interests and activities. His early years, 1891 to 1930, are represented by general correspondence covering the years, 1919-1927, his law school notebooks, 1912-1915, and a diary, 1925. There is no personal material prior to 1919 and none between 1927 and 1930. The only other pre-1930 material is correspondence and other material concerning the Harvard Law School Association that was given to Patterson during his presidency of the organization, 1937-1949.
The files for the years 1930-1940 are primarily concerned with legal matters and Patterson's judicial career. The only personal material from the period is correspondence pertaining principally to New York city and state politics.
The period 1940-1947, when Patterson served in the War Department, is well documented in the collection. As assistant secretary, then under secretary of war, 1940-1945, Patterson's primary responsibility was procurement and supply. Subjects covered in the correspondence, memoranda, and reports for the period include civilian versus military control of the wartime economy, military strategy, projected problems of the postwar world, and the difficulties involved in regulating and controlling a wartime economy. Of special interest is a file on wartime cabinet meetings that Patterson attended as a representative of the War Department.
Patterson's tenure as secretary of war, 1945-1947, is also well documented. Photocopies of his appointment books record in detail his daily activities for the period. Important subjects include cabinet meetings, the postwar settlement in Europe, switching from a wartime economy to a peacetime economy, the demobilization of the American military, and the projected merger of two cabinet departments into the Department of Defense. Patterson was an ardent believer in universal military training. Files on the issue can be found throughout the correspondence and the reports of the 1940s.
After his resignation as secretary of war in 1947, Patterson formed the legal firm of Patterson, Belknap, Webb and Tyler. Topics from the period include, the Marshall Plan, the United Nations, the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, and the embryonic European Common Market. Patterson served actively on such organizations as the American Association for the United Nations, the American Committee on United Europe, the Atlantic Union Committee, the United States Committee for a United Nations Genocide Convention, the Committee on the Permanent Court of Arbitration, and the United States Commission on Organization of the Executive Branch of the Government (1947-1953, the first Hoover Commission). Also covered is Patterson's chairmanship of the Long Island Rail Road Commission and his chairmanship of the American Bar Association Commission on Organized Crime. Of interest as well is a file concerning Francis Joseph Cardinal Spellman and the war claims of the Vatican in the late 1940s. Patterson was a strong supporter of civil rights as evidenced by the file on Freedom House and correspondence with Walter Francis White, executive secretary of the NAACP.
Correspondents in the collection include Henry Harley Arnold, Thurman Wesley Arnold, Bernard M. Baruch, Francis Biddle, Chester Bowles, Nicholas Murray Butler, James F. Byrnes, Benjamin N. Cardozo, Bennett Champ Clark, Mark W. Clark, Lucius D. Clay, James Bryant Conant, Homer S. Cummings, Elmer Holmes Davis, Thomas E. Dewey, James Harold Doolittle, Paul H. Douglas, Hugh Aloysius Drum, David Dubinsky, Allen Dulles, Dwight D. Eisenhower, James A. Farley, James Forrestal, Felix Frankfurter, Philip L. Graham, Erwin N. Griswold, Ernest Gruening, Augustus Noble Hand, Learned Hand, Alger Hiss, Anna Rosenberg Hoffman, Herbert Hoover, Charles Evans Hughes, Philip C. Jessup, Jesse H. Jones, Louis Arthur Johnson, Lyndon B. Johnson, Estes Kefauver, Ernest Joseph King, Julius Klein, Alfred A. Knopf, William S. Knudsen, James McCauley Landis, Herbert H. Lehman, David Eli Lilienthal, Robert A. Lovett, W. G. McAdoo, Douglas MacArthur, Patton Pat McCarran, J. Howard McGrath, George C. Marshall, Sherman Minton, Robert Moses, Donald Marr Nelson, Louis Nizer, William O'Dwyer, George S. Patton (1885-1945), Philip B. Perlman, Howard C. Peterson, Roscoe Pound, Owen J. Roberts, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Kenneth C. Royall, Samuel I. Rosenman, Leverett Saltonstall, Arthur M. Schlesinger (1917-2007), Alexander P. de Seversky, Robert E. Sherwood, Spyros Panagiotes Skouras, H. Alexander Smith, Lawrence E. Spivak, Brehon Burke Somervell, Francis Spellman, Henry L Stimson, Herbert Bayard Swope, Stuart Symington, Harry S. Truman, Millard E. Tydings, Arthur T. Vanderbilt, Tracy S. Voorhees, Robert F. Wagner (1877-1953), Walter Francis White, and Charles Edward Wilson.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is arranged in eight series:
Correspondence, 1909-1952
Legal File, 1913-1940
Speech File, 1940-1951
Miscellany, 1925-1956
Scrapbooks, 1941-1946
Under Secretary of War Files, 1940-1945
2023 Addition, 1947-1952
Classified, 1941-1943
Container List
- Correspondence, 1909-1952 (Box 1-49)
  - Harvard Law School Association, 1909-1925 (Box 1-2)
    Letters sent and received, financial data, memoranda, reports, and printed matter.
    Arranged chronologically.
    - 1909-1922, (8 folders) (Box 1)
    - 1923-1925, (6 folders) (Box 2)
  - General, 1919-1927 (Box 3-4)
    Letters sent and received, memoranda, reports, and some printed matter.
    - 1919-1925, (13 folders) (Box 3)
    - 1925-1927, (11 folders) (Box 4)
  - General, 1930-1945 (Box 5-17)
    Letters sent and received, memoranda, reports, and printed matter.
    Arranged alphabetically by subject and therein chronologically.
    - "A" miscellaneous (Box 5)
    - Adler, Julius O.
    - Allen, William
    - Amberg, Julius H.
    - American Bar Association
    - American Battle Monuments Commission
    - American Law Book Co.
    - American Law Institute
    - Angell, B. Montgomery
    - Appreciation letters
    - Arkwright, George
    - "Available Jones"
    - "B" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Bailey, Frank
    - Baldwin, Lila
    - Bar associations
    - Berenson, Lawrence
    - Berkley, Chair Co.
    - Bowden, W. M.
    - Breland, Homer
    - Brooklyn Law School, St. Lawrence University, Brooklyn, N.Y.
    - Bryant, Frederick B.
    - Buckner, Emory R.
    - Bull, Charles M. Jr.
    - Bullitt, William C.
    - Burlingham, Charles C.
    - "C" miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box 6)
    - Cabinet meetings
    - Caffey, Francis
    - Cards and notes
    - Caribbean trip, 1942
    - Cellar, Emanuel
    - Chadbourne, William M.
    - Chase, Harrie B.
    - Circuit court of appeals
    - Clancy, Jack
    - Clark, Grenville, (5 folders)
    - Clark, William
    - Cohen, Benjamin
    - Coleman, Samuel C.
    - Columbia University, New York, N.Y.
    - Compton, George
    - Conant, James
    - Congratulatory letters (Box 7)
      - 1930, (10 folders)
      - 1939, (9 folders) (Box 8)
      - 1940, (7 folders) (Box 9)
    - Continental Securities Corp.
    - Cornell Law School, Ithaca, N.Y.
    - Court clerk (Charles Weiser)
    - Cowan case (Dickinson Industrial Site v. Cowan)
    - Crittenden, Walter H.
    - "D" miscellaneous (Box 10)
    - Distinguished Service Medals
    - Division Association, Seventy Seventh
    - "E" miscellaneous
    - Ellenwood, Ernest J.
    - Ernst, Irving L.
    - European trip, 1944, (3 folders)
    - Evarts, William M.
    - Ewing, Caruthers
    - Exhibits
    - "F" miscellaneous
    - Federal Bar Association
    - Federal Grand Jury Association
    - Fish, Hamilton (1888-1991)
    - Foy, Richard
    - Frankfurter, Felix
    - "G" miscellaneous
    - Gammack, Thomas
    - Gerdes, John
    - Gluck, Edward
    - Goddar, Harry
    - Goodrich, Herbert F.
    - Gottlieb, Charles
    - Greenman, Frederick F.
    - Gurfein, Murray I.
    - "H" miscellaneous (Box 11)
    - Hadley, Morris
    - Hale, Thomas S.
    - Hall, Mrs. John T.
    - Haller, Kate
    - Hand, Augustus N.
    - Hand, Learned
    - Handler, Milton
    - Hardy, Lamar
    - Harvard Law School, Cambridge, Mass.
      - General, (2 folders)
      - Reunion of class of 1915, (2 folders)
    - Harvard Law School Association, (9 folders)
    - Haven's Relief Fund Society (Box 12)
    - Haviland, John C.
    - Hincks, Carroll C.
    - Hoopes, James and Maurice
    - "I-J" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Jackson, Percival
    - Joint Conference on Legal Education
    - Jones, Catesby L.
    - Judges' letters, (7 folders)
    - Justice Department, (2 folders)
    - "K" miscellaneous
    - Kapsalis, Peter T.
    - Keenan, Joseph
    - Klapp, John W.
    - Knight, Richard
    - Knollenberg, Bernhard
    - Knox, John
    - "L" miscellaneous
    - Landes, Lewis (Box 13)
    - Leavell, John H.
    - Levy, Matthew M.
    - Lewis, Albert D.
    - Lewis, William D.
    - Licker, Ralph H.
    - Lowell, James A.
    - Lyethe, J. M. Richardson
    - McAdoo, W. G.
    - McClennen, Edward F.
    - "M" miscellaneous
    - Mack, Julian W.
    - Manton, Martin T.
    - Maritime Law Association
    - Marsh, John B.
    - Middleton, Thomas H.
    - Middleton, E. Willoughby, (2 folders)
    - Military operations in Germany
    - Military Training Camps Association
    - Milbank and Associates
    - Milbrook School, Milbrook, N.Y.
    - Mills, Andrew
    - Mills, Henry
    - Montague, Gilbert H.
    - Moral Rearmament, Inc.
    - Moses, Charles K.
    - Murray, Lindley
    - "N" miscellaneous
    - New York Bar Association
    - New York Central Railroad
    - New York County Lawyer's Association
    - New York Law Society
    - New York Patent Law Association
    - New York State Bar Association
    - New York State Tax Commission
    - New York Times
    - New York University School of Law, New York, N.Y.
    - New York Young Democrats Club
    - "O" miscellaneous (Box 14)
    - Oath of appointment 1930
    - O'Brien, John P.
    - O'Connor, Basil
    - "P" miscellaneous
    - Patterson, Robert T.
    - Perkins, George
    - Pfeiffer, Timothy N.
    - Phillipstown Electric Corp.
    - Pound, Roscoe
    - Practicing Law Institute, New York, N.Y.
    - Press releases, (4 folders)
    - Pruyn estate
    - Quartermaster Corps
    - "R" miscellaneous (Box 15)
    - Racketeering
    - Randolph, Francis F.
    - Receiverships and trusteeships
    - Recommendations, (2 folders)
    - Rental of property
    - Reed, J. Duff
    - References in bankruptcy
    - Rogers, Edward A.
    - Root, Elihu Jr.
    - Ross, Joseph H.
    - Ruppertsburg, William
    - Russell, C. Allen
    - "S" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Salvini, Armand
    - Scott, Austin, W.
    - Scott, Lloyd N.
    - Sears, Roebuck and Co.
    - Seaton, Charles S.
    - Securities and Exchange Commission
    - Seewald, Edward Y.
    - Seligson, Charles
    - Seventy-Seventh Division
    - Seversky, Alexander P. de
    - Silverstein, Samuel (Box 16)
    - Simpson, Sidney P.
    - South Pacific trip, 1943, (3 folders)
    - Special Committee to Study the Bar, (2 folders)
    - Spielberg, George A.
    - State Mutual Life Insurance Co.
    - Steinhardt, Maxwell
    - Steward, William B.
    - "T" miscellaneous
    - Tenaglia, Louis
    - Tener, Alexander C.
    - Thacher, Archibald G.
    - Todd, Hiram C.
    - Tuttle, Charles H. (Box 17)
    - Tweed, Harrison H.
    - "U" miscellaneous
    - Uniacke, Joseph B.
    - Union College, Schenectady, N.Y.
    - University of the State of New York, Albany, N.Y.
    - "V" miscellaneous
    - Veterans Administration
    - "W" miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Wadsworth, J. W.
    - Wagner, Robert F.
    - Wainwright, Matthew J.
    - Waldron, William
    - Walton, Charles W.
    - Webb, Vanderbilt
    - Weisman, M. Murray
    - Welfare agencies
    - Weaton, Carl C.
    - White, Robert V.
    - White, Walter
    - Wickersham, Cornelius W.
    - Wilkins, Raymond S.
    - Williston, Samuel
    - Wilson, Myron K.
    - Wise, Raymond L.
    - Woolsey, John M.
    - "Y-Z" miscellaneous
    - Yale University, New Haven, Conn.
    - Zimmerman and Forshay case
  - General, 1945-1947 (Box 18-23)